Prateek Nigam

prateeknigam9@gmail.com

https://github.com/prateeknigam9

https://www.linkedin.com/in/prateeknigam9

Mobile No: +91 9039871619

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

IT Professional with around 5 years of experience in the industry, currently working on a Market mix modeling project to implement an analytics model and cultivate insights from data. Have exposure to building data models and applying machine and deep learning algorithms. Have sound mathematical knowledge and understanding of machine learning.

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Technical: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Python, Natural Language Processing, SQL, Decision Tree, Random Forest, SVM, TensorFlow, Keras, Pandas, Matplotlib, Clustering, Sequential Models, Custom models, Transformers, attention Models, RNN

EDUCATION

Acropolis Institute of Technology and Research, India Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication

2015- 2019

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist - Fractal Analytics **Projects** -

Oct 2021 - Present

- Worked as subject matter expert in MMM (Market Mix Modeling) across Multiple product categories for P&G.
- Supported the automation & scaling initiative of MMM data and modeling it to strategize investments.
- Build end-to-end MMM data processing in the MMM team.
- Implemented different traditional modeling / ML techniques and drew insights through statistical techniques and predictive modeling.
- Analyze and investigate data trends and identify data anomalies.
- Working and implementing all facets of analytics descriptive, prescriptive, and predictive analysis, and effectively communicating the results to various internal/external team members.

Software Engineer - Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd. **Projects** -

Aug 2019 - Oct 2021

- Collaborated with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on evolving client requirements.
- Contributed to enhancing PySpark transformation ETL tool
- Tuned and improved tool code based on new user requirements and technical guidelines.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs, and enhancements.
- Implemented SSO on the web application using Kerberos and query LDAP for filtering AD groups.
- Produced advanced and clean code for diverse applications.
- Developed microservices on application environments using flask

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

- Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd. Rising Star award
- **Sopa Cognitive Analytics** Internship (May 2019 Aug 2019)
- Academic Certificates Applied Machine Learning (Applied AI), Neural Networks and Deep Learning, Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp, MLOPS (in progress)

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Language Translation with Attention Models (GitHub)
- Semantic Engine Search Engine that uses AI to learn and search FAQs on customer queries
- Predict the Popularity of memes on Reddit (Blog at medium.com)
- Jane Street Stock Market (Blog Medium.com)